Who broke the internet?
Ralph Breaks the Internet is a family, animation,
comedy film directed by Phil Johnston.
Video game bad guy Ralph and fellow misfit Vanellope von Schweetz must risk it all by traveling to the
World Wide Web in search of a replacement part to save Vanellope's video game, Sugar Rush.
In way over their heads, Ralph and Vanellope rely on the citizens of the internet — the netizens — to help navigate their way,
including an entrepreneur named Yesss, who is the head algorithm and the heart and soul of trend-making site BuzzzTube.
Wreck-It Ralph (voice), played by John C. Reilly.
Vanellope von Schweetz (voice), played by Sarah Silverman.
Shank (voice), played by Gal Gadot.
Yesss (voice), played by Taraji P. Henson.
J.P. Spamley (voice) (uncredited), played by Bill Hader.
Felix (voice), played by Jack McBrayer.
Ralph Breaks the Internet is a 2018 American animated comedy
film produced by Walt Disney Animation Studios.
The film was directed by Rich Moore and Phil Johnston
and written by Johnston and Pamela Ribon.
Reilly, Sarah Silverman, Jack McBrayer, Jane Lynch, and Ed O'Neill reprise their
character roles from the first film, with Gal Gadot, Taraji P.
Henson, and Alfred Molina joining the cast.
Alan Tudyk also returns, voicing a different character.
The sequel to Wreck-It Ralph (2012), the film follows Ralph and Vanellope von Schweetz, who must travel to the
internet to get a replacement for the Sugar Rush cabinet's broken steering wheel and prevent Mr.
Litwak from disposing of the game.
Discussions about a sequel to Wreck-It Ralph began in September 2012, and the new installment went
through three different scripts before the filmmakers settled on the final plot.
When the film was officially announced in June 2016, most of the original cast
confirmed they had signed on, with new cast members added in 2018.
The film's title of Ralph Breaks the Internet was announced in March 2017.
Ralph Breaks the Internet premiered in Hollywood, Los Angeles, on November 5,
2018, and was released in the United States on November 21.
The film received generally positive reviews from critics and was a box office
success, grossing $529 million worldwide against a $175 million budget.
It was nominated for Best Animated Feature at the 91st Academy Awards, 76th Golden
Globe Awards, 46th Annie Awards, and 24th Critics' Choice Awards.
The film explores themes of video game, cartoon, sequel, internet, lethal virus.
The tone is lighthearted.